biblionasium.com 2018-08-25

# Biblionasium - Kids Share Book Recommendations. Use Online Reading Logs, Find Books At Their Reading Level

## Privacy Policy

Updated November 1, 2016

Welcome to Biblionasium, a fun and engaging website to excite and encourage kids to read. On Biblionasium, with a parent and/or educator permission, children are given an account where they can then catalogue and track their reading, connect to friends to share and exchange book reviews and recommendations, discover new books, and get rewards for completing reading challenges. Parents and teachers also participate by monitoring the children’s reading, reviews, give book recommendations and create challenges for the children and help them meet their reading goals.

We respect and protect all of our users' privacy and have built a safe online platform to support and promote the independent reading activities of children, 13 years of age and younger. Because our users are 13 and younger, we take extra precautions to keep everyone on Biblionasium safe and protected. Our information practices are designed to comply with the United States Federal Trade Commission's (FTC) Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Our Privacy Policy will help you understand the different measures we take to help create a safe and fun digital platform for kids.

To find out more about COPPA, please visit <https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule>. 

Please read through this Privacy Policy, and take some time to talk with your child about the importance of being safe on the Internet. We believe the Internet is a special tool that can open up a world of great opportunities for kids, but not everyone on the web has good intentions. Remember to stay involved in your kids' and students' activity on Biblionasium and any other sites they visit as they explore the World Wide Web.

### PRIVO-Cert™ Safe Harbor Certification Program:

Biblionasium is a Member of the PRIVO's PRIVO-Cert™ Safe Harbor Certification Program (“the Program”). As a participating member in the Program, Biblionasium adheres to the strict information collection, use and disclosure requirements set forth by the Program. PRIVO is an independent, third-party organization committed to safeguarding children's personal information collected online. PRIVO aims to help parents and their children exercise control over personal information while exploring the Internet. The PRIVO certification seal posted on this page indicates that Biblionasium has established COPPA compliant privacy practices and has agreed to submit to PRIVO's oversight and consumer dispute resolution process. If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us at 917-5-Biblio (917 524-2546) or info@biblionasium.com. If you have further concerns after you have contacted us, you can contact PRIVO directly at privacy@privo.com.

### Registration and Account Information

Biblionasium does not allow children 13 years of age and younger to have an account until their parent, legal guardian, or teacher creates one for them. If you are 13 years of age or younger, you may not sign up for Biblionasium on your own. A parent or legal guardian must provide a valid email and after confirming that information, we allow them to open an account for the child. Educators with verified email addresses, can also register student ids. However, we do not ask, and Educators cannot enter any personal information about their students. We only request a first name and last name initial to personalize and address the children by a name on the website when they log in, and if necessary to generate a unique and anonymous userid for the students. Otherwise, the parent or educator has to create a unique userid for the child. Userids should not contain any personally identifiable information.

We also do not require, nor collect email addresses for the children.

If a child accesses our site and wishes to register, they are able to enter an email address for their parent, so that we can contact and notify the parent of their interest. After the email is sent to the parent, the parent email address is deleted. Parents can elect to register on the site and become a member.

### Cookies:

We use cookies to help us keep track of your data. Cookies are small files that carry non-personal information that you provide to a website. They are kind of like a cheat-sheet for your computer--on its own, your computer does not remember who you are as you move throughout a website. Cookies store that information and provide it every time the information is needed. Without cookies, you would have to sign in with your username and password every time you went to a different page of our site!

### IP Information:

When you browse onto a website, your Internet Protocol (IP) address is automatically shared with that site. Other information such as where you arrived to the site from, what type of browser you are using, and your general region could also be shared. Like many websites on the Internet, we keep track of this information to help us better understand how many and how our users are using Biblionasium. We do not track your activity outside of our Services.

### Email Addresses

We do not require, collect or store email addresses for children. However, parents and educators using our platform to register children, need to provide a valid email address. We use the email address to respond to your questions, send emails about maintenance and updates, send notifications relating to your children's on-site activities and for internal marketing research purposes. At the time of registration, parents and educators can additionally opt-in or opt-out of receiving email notification for offers, discounts or promotions from Biblionasium, our sponsors, or 3rd party partners that support our site.

### Other Information we collect

All users on Biblionasium have the option to add books to their virtual bookshelves. They can also tag, rate, review and recommend books. This information is saved with the user's account. If you are a parent or educator, your book information is shared with the children under the supervision of your account. For registered children, this information is shared with the adult supervisor(s) on their account, as well the other children that have been permitted and have been approved to be part of their community.

Biblionasium also uses this information to improve our products and services and aggregate data may be used with our partners and sponsors. No personally identifiable information is shared without explicit consent. While no Personal information is shared, aggregate data may be used to offer valuable book and reading related products and services to our users.

For the benefit of our community and our users, we may choose to share and make selected book reviews, written by our users, available to all our members. We will screen and carefully elect those reviews for suitability and safety, and to make sure there is no personally identifiable information disclosed.

### How we keep your information safe:

Biblionasium has taken several measures to keep your information safe. Our data is stored on secure servers and we use all industry standards to protect against hacking. We use Network Solutions SSL to encrypt all and any personal information whenever it is transmitted over the wire.

We use select service providers for some of the operational aspects of the website. These providers are subject to legal restrictions that prohibit their user of the information for any purpose other than to facilitate the specific outsourced related operation, unless you have explicitly given your permission for additional uses.

We use Google Analytics to better understand your use of our website and to improve your experience. This third party does not share your information with any other third parties. To find out more about Google Analytics [click here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

### How we keep your child's information safe:

If a child is registered by a parent, the parent is required to provide a first name, last name initial, and a username with which the child will use to access the website. A parent also has the option to provide any or none of the following information: the child’s birthdate, gender, reading level and school. None of this information is required for a child to use the website. Any additional information provided, is used to enhance and personalize their experience. If we have any personal information about that child, then only friends and family, who are approved by the parent, can see those pieces of information. Other signed in users may be able to see their anonymous username, books, reviews, anonymous names of their friends and other non-personal information. People who are not signed in to Biblionasium are not able to see any user information on our site. A verified parent must authorize all users who see any of the child´s personal information through Biblionasium. However, it is important to remember that any information that you put on the Internet could become public. There is no such thing as “fail-safe” on the Internet, and we are not responsible for any 3rd party distribution of the information you provide. Please talk to your child about the importance of being safe while using the Internet.

When a teacher registers a student, we only require a first name and a last name initial. We use this information to generate a unique and anonymous userid, if none is provided. All students registered by a teacher and belonging to a unique classroom, are able to see each other’s bookshelves. Students can recommend books to students in their group or class. Children can also recommend books to “friends” who have been approved by the parent on the account.

In addition, educators can select to have student book reviews shared with other members of their group, or not shared at all. If they do want to give permission for shared book reviews, they still have another layer of control. Educators can select to have student Book reviews shared with the rest of the group automatically and as they are written, or they can select to have reviews published and available to the rest of the group, only upon teacher approval. Educators have full control of this feature. We highly recommend and suggest that if you wish to turn on the “Book Review Sharing” feature, that you set parameters and discuss the importance of writing responsibly and safely with your students. Biblionasium does not endorse or take responsibility for the content that students write on the site.

For more information about how to help children socialize responsibly on the Internet, please visit <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/tech/tec13.shtm>. 

### Disclosing Information

We may disclose Personal Information if we have to comply with legal obligations or to law enforcement requests, to protect and defend our rights and property or the safety of other users, and with your permission.

If we are involved in a change in control, merger, acquisition, reorganization, receivership, bankruptcy, transition of Services to another provider, or any similar transaction, your information may be transferred or sold as permitted by law and/or contract. We will use reasonable efforts to notify you before information about you is transferred and if the policies of the acquiring company are different so you can select to continue or discontinue the service.

### Third Party Affiliations and Links

Biblionasium is offered free of charge for use to kids, their educators and parents. We support the operations, development and activities of the platform through mission aligned sponsorships, 3rd party partners and an e-commerce component that provides the option to purchase books from our site, to our adult users. While we may use information collected on the site to enable book related discovery and promotion from our sponsors, we DO NOT SHARE, SELL, RENT or TRADE THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION OF OUR USERS WITH ANY THIRD PARTIES, without obtaining the users’ explicit consent. Our website may also contain links to sponsor products or services that offer book related support material, content, teacher’s guides, book widgets, author interviews, book trailers and such. While we take great caution and screen the material, we are not responsible for the practices and privacy policy of other sites. Please read and be familiar with their practices, as we only have control and cover the use of Information we gather on Biblionasium. You assume sole responsibility for your use of any third party links and sites.

We may use multi-media, audio and high quality videos to introduce and excite our users to explore book titles and authors. We closely curate and select any multi-media content for safety and suitability, whether they are chosen by our editors or offered by our sponsors. Educators have the option to include or exclude multi-media content from Book Information pages. We do not disclose Personal Information to Third Party hosting sites, but you should be aware that any information that you disclose once you access other websites is not subject to this Privacy Policy.

In order to support the operations of the site and to develop and include all the features, we also provide links for adults to purchase books from third party providers, who in return pay us a small affiliate fee. We may also aggregate and share or sell anonymous data, including but not limited to, ratings and reviews. We do not share or sell any personally identifiable information with a third party without explicit permission.

### Leaving the community:

If you are having trouble using or enjoying Biblionasium, or would like to review, update or have your account deleted, please contact us right away at help@Biblionasium.com. However, if you decide you no longer want to be a part of Biblionasium you have the right to terminate your students´, your child´s, and your own account. You can do this by going to “Settings” menu while you are signed in and following the instructions to remove yourself as a user. Please consider contacting us with any questions or concerns that might lead to leaving our community.

### Other information:

We reserve the right to update this policy when we deem necessary. You will be notified of any changes to this Privacy Policy by the publication of a revised policy on this page. It is your responsibility to check back to this page from time to time to ensure that you are up to date on any modifications. If we make a material change to this policy we will contact you by email before the changes become effective to seek your consent.

Biblionasium was founded by the parents and educators at Biblio Holdings LLC. You can contact us by email ([contact@Biblionasium.com](mailto:contact@Biblionasium.com)) or writing to us at PO Box 1034, New York, NY 10150. Any use of the words “us”, “we”, “our”, “Biblionasium” and “Biblionasium.com” in this Privacy Policy refers to Biblio Holdings LLC.
